<?xml version='1.1' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<xwikidoc version="1.3" reference="Cached Articles.Hannity Show 2020-04-21.WebHome" locale="">
  <web>Cached Articles.Hannity Show 2020-04-21</web>
  <name>WebHome</name>
  <language/>
  <defaultLanguage>en</defaultLanguage>
  <translation>0</translation>
  <creator>XWiki.atripp</creator>
  <creationDate>1589378414000</creationDate>
  <parent>Cached Articles.WebHome</parent>
  <author>XWiki.atripp</author>
  <contentAuthor>XWiki.atripp</contentAuthor>
  <date>1589378415000</date>
  <contentUpdateDate>1589378414000</contentUpdateDate>
  <version>1.2</version>
  <title>Hannity Show 2020-04-21</title>
  <comment>Update document after refactoring.</comment>
  <minorEdit>true</minorEdit>
  <syntaxId>xwiki/2.1</syntaxId>
  <hidden>false</hidden>
  <content>Busy night tonight on HANNITY. Thank you for joining us.&#xd;
&#xd;
Now, the president tonight once again taking bold action to secure the American people. Sad when you really stop and think this is about lives, isn't it? Our fellow Americans, seriousness involved in this. You wouldn't know it from the media, Democrats.&#xd;
&#xd;
Now, the one guy that was ahead of the curve as it relates to China, travel bans, the need to secure America's borders is now taking another important measure to protect we, the American people, and our jobs.&#xd;
&#xd;
Take a look.&#xd;
&#xd;
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)&#xd;
&#xd;
DONALD TRUMP, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES: We have a solemn duty to ensure these unemployed Americans regain their jobs and their livelihoods therefore in order to protect American workers. I will be issuing a temporary suspension of immigration into the United States, you heard about that last night.&#xd;
&#xd;
By pausing immigration, we will help put unemployed Americans first in line for jobs as America reopens, so important. It would be wrong and unjust for Americans laid off by the virus to be replaced with new immigrant labor flown in from abroad.&#xd;
&#xd;
(END VIDEO CLIP)&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: Now, certain essential workers will reportedly be exempt from the immigration suspension. That would include doctors on the front lines battling COVID-19, other health workers.&#xd;
&#xd;
And Americans, we always welcome immigrants. But the president's right to secure our borders. Why? We need to vet people, make sure that they don't have radical ties.&#xd;
&#xd;
We have to make sure now, people are healthy, not to be invasive, to make sure they're healthy to protect the American people. They have to be able to provide for themselves and, yes, 90 percent of America's heroin crosses that border. We need to do it for that reason as well. Then, by the way, welcome to our great American family.&#xd;
&#xd;
The 60-day suspension will give us time to assess our economy, give Americans time to get back to work hopefully sooner than later. What we have now witnessed in the past several months, the media mob will never tell you, Democrats will never acknowledge, it is unprecedented, and so is this administration's response.&#xd;
&#xd;
We are now witnessing right before our very eyes what has been and is the greatest medical mobilization this country has ever seen. President Trump vowed to get states all the critical supplies, the resources they need, so many states, most states, most governors were not prepared for anything, no emergency. He's delivered in the promise in a big way.&#xd;
&#xd;
And so far, the federal government has distributed 57.4 million N95 masks and they're being built as we speak, 85.3 million surgical masks, 6.4 million face shields, 12.3 million surgical gowns, 638 million sets of gloves, nearly 11,000 respirators, the strategic stockpile still has, what, nearly 10,000 ventilators in storage. That number is surging. The GM assembly line is now working and they are producing every day.&#xd;
&#xd;
Over the next week, more than 500 will be delivered as promised. We had thousands more than we ever needed. Tens of thousands more will soon be on the way. The president and his team triggering the Defense Production Act worked.&#xd;
&#xd;
And thanks to all these great American businesses -- by the way, they never stopped working. They kept supplying our hospitals, our heroes on the front line, our doctors, our nurses, our janitors and hospitals, the real heroes here, well, they were being supported by people that didn't stop working --just like the food was going on the shelves and the medicines were in your pharmacies even in states like New York.&#xd;
&#xd;
They all stepped up to the plate. They never stopped working. They never shut down. FFarmers farmed, packers packed, truckers trucked. And thank God, those would stock those shelves and they stayed stock.&#xd;
&#xd;
Meanwhile, the United States also leading the world on testing, no country even close. It has tested more of its citizens than any other country. Many countries combined as a matter of fact.&#xd;
&#xd;
The president mobilized our great military, over 5,500 U.S. military personnel, they have been deployed across two dozen hospitals; 28,700 National Guard heroes, they're now on duty as well. By the way, the Javits Center, that personnel came from the president, same with the Comfort, that personnel came from the president.&#xd;
&#xd;
Let's not forget about Project Airbridge. That's the public-private partnership was organized by the White House. It sent massive U.S. cargo planes to pick up crucial medical supplies from factories around the world and get them here as fast as possible. So far, 64 flights have been completed and at least 50 more are scheduled.&#xd;
&#xd;
This massive mobilization did not happen overnight, didn't happen by chance either. From the very first days of the virus, the president has taken one bold action after another to protect American lives.&#xd;
&#xd;
There's an op-ed in "The Wall Street Journal" rightly pointed out President Trump acted with dispatch to keep Americans safe, even when it was unpopular like on January 31st when President Trump banned travel to and from China. Then, the first quarantine in over 50 years, then subsequent travel bans.&#xd;
&#xd;
The mob, the media raced to call him racist. They said he overreacted. "The New York Times", geniuses that they are, they indicated days later, perfectly safe to travel to China. Hmm, I wonder if anyone followed "The New York Times'" horrific advice. Hmm. Inquiring minds want to know.&#xd;
&#xd;
The more confused than ever Joe Biden called the president xenophobic, hysterical, accused of a fear-mongering, and all the while ,Democrats, what were they doing on Capitol Hill? They were consumed by their impeachment stunt. They weren't focused on the coronavirus, just criticizing the travel ban.&#xd;
&#xd;
Days earlier, Nancy Pelosi -- remember, she was signing and handing out those commemorative impeachment pens and taking selfies. On February 4th, during the president's State of the Union Address, yes, as he was talking about the coronavirus, she was busy with another political stunt pre-ripping and then officially ripping up the speech pre-planned temper tantrum for the cameras.&#xd;
&#xd;
February 24th, that genius that loves ice cream, she went down to the crowded streets of San Francisco's Chinatown, encouraged everyone to come visit. In March, the left was totally preoccupied with their insane political narrative that the president was racist for calling the coronavirus Wuhan or the China coronavirus, even though the virus originated in Wuhan in China.&#xd;
&#xd;
Remember this.&#xd;
&#xd;
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)&#xd;
&#xd;
SUSAN RICE, FORMER OBAMA NATIONAL SECURITY ADVISOR: We are not behaving well when we talk about, as the president does every day, the Chinese virus, the Wuhan flu, and all of these racist descriptions.&#xd;
&#xd;
REPORTER: Why do you keep using this? A lot are saying it's racist.&#xd;
&#xd;
TRUMP: Because it comes from China.&#xd;
&#xd;
REPORTER: This is a virus that came from the territory of China but came from bats. This is a bat virus, not a China virus. It doesn't speak Chinese.&#xd;
&#xd;
UNIDENTIFIED MALE: The president says no, this is not racist at all. But, of course, it's nakedly racist, and obviously racist, and blatantly racist.&#xd;
&#xd;
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: For the president to call it a Chinese virus or a foreign virus, that is just not -- it's just so dangerous.&#xd;
&#xd;
(END VIDEO CLIP)&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: And while the mob and the media spent March using the virus as a political weapon, which they did, other top Democrats, they were still playing down the severity of the pandemic.&#xd;
&#xd;
Now, Comrade de Blasio, March the 2nd, he was encouraging New Yorkers to go out on the town, catch a plague. The governor, he claimed the disease wouldn't be as bad in New York as other countries -- wrong on both parts.&#xd;
&#xd;
New York is an international city. New York City is more densely populated than any other place in America. Geographically, the smallest, with the highest concentration of people, far more risk for a terrorist attack and viral outbreaks than anyone else in the country. Yet, the city of New York was woefully unprepared.&#xd;
&#xd;
In fact, sometime after 2016, Comrade de Blasio, their ever complaining mayor, actually auctioned off the city's reserve ventilators. But he doesn't know who got them. And the city's stockpile of PPE supplies -- well, they were virtually non-existent.&#xd;
&#xd;
So, when the virus exploded, which was predictable because they had multiple studies, including the city of New York, the federal government came to the rescue and rightfully so. It was the president, he ordered the construction of numerous emergency hospitals in and around New York. He staffed them for the mayor with federal personnel.&#xd;
&#xd;
He sent the USNS Comfort to New York harbor. He staffed it with his personnel. He ordered the Army Corps of Engineers and FEMA to construct a massive, the largest in the country, temporary hospital at the Javits Center.&#xd;
&#xd;
And he ordered both the ship and the Javits Center to be converted to accept COVID patients -- not an easy thing to do. You have to change the ventilation, everything else. They got it done.&#xd;
&#xd;
And the president also sent all the ventilators and millions of medical supplies and medicine that de Blasio never had. But Comrade de Blasio not particularly grateful, shamefully standing in front of a microphone, accusing the president of leaving New Yorkers to die -- can't make this up. He said it. Watch.&#xd;
&#xd;
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)&#xd;
&#xd;
MAYOR BILL DE BLASIO (D), NEW YORK CITY: I remember famously in the 1970s when one of your predecessors, Gerald Ford, didn't care to help New York City during the fiscal crisis. There was that famous "Daily News" cover that said, Ford to city: drop dead.&#xd;
&#xd;
So my question is Mr. Trump, Mr. President, are you going to save New York City or are you telling New York City to drop dead?&#xd;
&#xd;
(END VIDEO CLIP)&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: Comrade de Blasio, if President Trump didn't bail you're sorry, unprepared ass out, guess what? Many more New Yorkers in your city would have died. Many more would have been infected, many more would have been hospitalized and nobody would have had a ventilator.&#xd;
&#xd;
Instead, New York City, thanks to President Trump, you can thank him, Mr. Mayor, and seeing thankfully a precipitous decline in hospitalizations intubations a death rate not fast enough but is also declining.&#xd;
&#xd;
Comrade de Blasio, he should be thanking the president, because he built and manned the hospitals for you, Mr. Mayor. He sent you the ventilators you sold. He sent you the medical equipment you never had, knowing that the threats were real for New York.&#xd;
&#xd;
Now, you should be held accountable for your complete ineptitude, incompetence and frankly your kind of ungrateful too, because the American taxpayers we're paying for all of that. That means people outside of New York, you can thank them too.&#xd;
&#xd;
This brings us to something we've never -- we've got to notice over the past several weeks, now while the president faces a hostile press corps every single solitary second of every day -- now, by the way, Governor Cuomo met with the president in New York, the president -- the governor to his credit has consistently praised the president -- well, a few minor hiccups here and there, but to his credit, the governor's been thankful. The governor of New York has worked with the president daily.&#xd;
&#xd;
But we have noticed the liberal media mob does treat him differently than President Trump. He faces a far less hostile mob in the media. A quick example.&#xd;
&#xd;
(BEGIN VIDEOI CLIP)&#xd;
&#xd;
REPORTER: Is it possible that your impulse to put a positive spin on things may be giving Americans a false sense of --&#xd;
&#xd;
(CROSSTALK)&#xd;
&#xd;
TRUMP: No, I don't think so.&#xd;
&#xd;
REPORTER: Marriage bureaus are closed right now, does the state have a way to help off marriage certificates?&#xd;
&#xd;
REPORTER: And where is Dr. Fauci?&#xd;
&#xd;
TRUMP: I don't know, but every time you ask that question, whenever he's not here, you look, you say, where is he and you'll say, is there a problem?&#xd;
&#xd;
REPORTER: How confident are you that you can get Congress to give you want you want?&#xd;
&#xd;
GOV. ANDREW CUOMO (D), NEW YORK: I'll talk to you tomorrow.&#xd;
&#xd;
How confident am I of federal responsibility and action? Not that confident.&#xd;
&#xd;
REPORTER: Today, we hit the grim milestone of more than 40,000 Americans now having died from the coronavirus. Can you explain then why you come out here and you were reading clips and showing clips of praise for you and for your administration?&#xd;
&#xd;
(END VIDEO CLIP)&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: What you just saw it's not shocking and I don't blame Governor Cuomo, but I do blame the mob and the media, because the same people, frankly, they've been many that have been rooting since Donald Trump became president that he fell from day one. The same mob that lied, smeared, slandered, besmirched, one conspiracy theory hoax after another. You know, they can't acknowledge a single good thing the president has done.&#xd;
&#xd;
People should ask the mob and the media, hey, in retrospect was the president's travel ban a good thing? Did the president do a good job building those hospitals for New York? Did the president do a good job of getting the ventilators built and all the medical supply sent to the ill-prepared mayor of New York?&#xd;
&#xd;
Even during a national emergency, the mob never changes. They will even politicize a virus because they so hate Donald Trump. That's how sick they are.&#xd;
&#xd;
But meanwhile, we have their timeline. March 8th, fake news CNN, it's Trump's Katrina -- yes, in the middle of Trump getting the supplies together.&#xd;
&#xd;
March 9th, "Washington Post", this is Erik Pimple's paper, calling it Donald Trump's Chernobyl.&#xd;
&#xd;
March 12th, when President Trump extended the travel ban to Europe, the mob slammed him for infecting international relations.&#xd;
&#xd;
March 13th, when the president declared a national emergency, "Time Magazine" called it an admission of failure.&#xd;
&#xd;
March 19th, fake news CNN claiming Trump's lack of imagination was costing American lives and treasure.&#xd;
&#xd;
March 30th, well, "The Boston Globe", not to be undone by anyone else in the mob, accusing the president of having blood on his hands.&#xd;
&#xd;
April 8th, the psychos over at MSDNC that live in that hole altered universe of theirs, well, they had one of their paid commentators and host saying that tens of thousands of people will die because of Trump's coronavirus incompetence.&#xd;
&#xd;
April 11th, "New York Times", very same paper encouraging Americans to travel to China after the travel ban -- dumb that they are -- they wrote the Trump should have seen the virus coming.&#xd;
&#xd;
He did the ban ten days after the first case. You, six days later, were telling people it's safe to travel to China. Yikes!&#xd;
&#xd;
Monday, very angry MSDNC -- by the way, former McCain for president liberal Steve Schmidt totally lost his mind.&#xd;
&#xd;
Steve, what's happened to you? Take a look.&#xd;
&#xd;
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)&#xd;
&#xd;
STEVE SCHMIDT, MSNBC ANALYST: More than 40,000 Americans are dead. This didn't have to be so. It's so because of the inaptitude of the White House response for years on from the promise of I'll make America great again and I alone can fix it, we can survey now the wreckage and the magnitude of the disaster in this country that has been wrought by the Trump presidency. The inaptitude of the federal government shows everybody around the world from ally to adversary of what a clown show American governance has become.&#xd;
&#xd;
(END VIDEO CLIP)&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: It's sad, predictable this kind of rhetoric. Really in the middle of a national emergency? It has real consequences.&#xd;
&#xd;
The mob and the media, they're breathless effort from day one of the presidency of Donald Trump literally make him into a villain -- lie, smear, slander, hoax, conspiracy, they did it all. They're totally letting the world's worst bad actor get off the hook.&#xd;
&#xd;
This virus started in Wuhan, China. The Chinese government attempted to cover it up. They lied to the world.&#xd;
&#xd;
They killed scientists, murdered doctors and suppressed important data that the world needed they shut down all domestic travel to and from Wuhan within China, but they kept international flights, going, protecting themselves, infecting the world. They should pay. And now, some in China might be profiteering off the virus.&#xd;
&#xd;
Here with more is the director of the Office of Trade and Manufacturing Policy, Peter Navarro.&#xd;
&#xd;
PETER NAVARRO, DIRECTOR, OFFICE OF TRADE AND MANUFACTURING POLICY: Good evening, Sean.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: Of all that China did, the fact that they shut down the travel, we'll get to the profits here, within China from -- out of Wuhan to China or from China to Wuhan, but left it open to the world, they knew how bad it was. They let the world get sick and die and they protected themselves.&#xd;
&#xd;
NAVARRO: Yes, the Chinese might call it the four kills, the killing of Americans. Let's walk through it.&#xd;
&#xd;
They spawned the virus probably in that P4 lab right there in China, and then they hid the virus behind the shield of the World Health Organization. Sean, what that did over a six-week period is allow hundreds of thousands of Wuhanians basically to get on aircraft and seed the world.&#xd;
&#xd;
While they were doing that, Sean, and this is just -- just disgusting, what they did was they vacuumed up all the world's masks, gloves, goggles, personal protective equipment, 2 billion masks, Sean, 2 billion masks. That's why in Milan, New York, and other places, our people didn't have them now, Sean, you know what they're doing, what they're doing is profiteering from this crisis, charging prices for a 50 cent mask of three for five dollars and more, and sending us counterfeit tests.&#xd;
&#xd;
That's the four kills, the killing of Americans and people internationally.&#xd;
&#xd;
And what's puzzling to me is why the mainstream media and the national Democrats don't get that. The Pew poll that came out today, Sean, was the most stunning affirmation of President Trump's leadership. Over 90 percent of Americans see China as a major threat, over 70 percent have an unfavorable view of China. It's across party lines.&#xd;
&#xd;
And I can't help but think of the nine percent that don't see China is a threat. They are the commentariat over at the fake news media and national Democrats like Nancy Pelosi and Joe Biden who basically don't want to blame anybody but Donald Trump for this -- this Wuhan virus. There I said it.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: Well, you know, it's sad but you think this would be an all-hands-on-deck moment? Obviously, it's not for a lot of people. But they do -- they do hold a lot of our debt. I would say China should pay.&#xd;
&#xd;
NAVARRO: Yes. Yes, one other thing I want to say about this, Sean, you know that story of the "four kills" story I just told you, that's the story "60 Minutes" should have told 10 days ago. They took two hours of taped interview and wound up using three minutes out of context to blame President Trump. And the dog that didn't bark in that segment was the fact that they didn't have a word of ill towards China in terms of their contribution to it.&#xd;
&#xd;
And I would say to the American people, you got it right in that Pew poll. You got it right when it's over 90 percent.&#xd;
&#xd;
And yes, Sean, we're going to have to hold China accountable when -- when this is over. But what I'm doing right now, Sean, is focusing on the supply chain to make sure that Americans at the front lines have the PPE and medicines they need, and we're going to have to bring those supply chains home right here to America.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: All right. Peter Navarro -- by the way, it looks like daylight. That is a live shot. It looks like it looks like -- it looks it's sunny behind you, your lighting is perfect there.&#xd;
&#xd;
NAVARRO: I got -- I got a north wind coming in here that as cold --&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: I see the trees.&#xd;
&#xd;
NAVARRO: -- as a Wuhan virus coming into this country.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: Well, let's get our country back up and working as fast as we can.&#xd;
&#xd;
NAVARRO: Sure. I love your timelines, by the way.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: Thank you. We work hard on them. Thanks.&#xd;
&#xd;
By the way, they're on Hannity.com.&#xd;
&#xd;
We got them for everybody. We got them for CNN, fake news. We got for "The New York Times", "Washington Post", all these politicians like ice cream-loving Pelosi -- come to Chinatown in February 24th. I got it all there, Hannity.com.&#xd;
&#xd;
Here with more, the host of "Lara Logan Has No Agenda", FOXNation.com, Laura Logan, former White House press secretary, FOX News contributor Sarah Sanders is with us.&#xd;
&#xd;
Sarah, I begin with you.&#xd;
&#xd;
You know, I know you lived through a lot of this and that is the mob hates the president. They hated him the day he came out on the escalator with Melania Trump. I don't expect them to change. You lived through Russia, Russia, Ukraine, Ukraine, impeach, impeach.&#xd;
&#xd;
But there's never been in history -- I want the media to answer questions. I'd like to ask them, in retrospect, was the travel ban a good decision? Next thing I'd like to say is, OK, what did the president do well in your opinion here? The hospitals he built, the hospitals he manned, the ventilators he built, the respirators he sent.&#xd;
&#xd;
Can they say anything good?&#xd;
&#xd;
SARAH SANDERS, FOX NEWS CONTRIBUTOR: You know, I don't think they can because they're so blinded by their hatred for this president and they care more about destroying him and tearing him down and trying to spread their message of negativity about this president than they do about building this country up. No matter how great of a job Donald Trump does, no matter how many lives he saves, no matter how many livelihoods he protects, it will never be enough for the mainstream liberal media. They really want to do nothing but destroy him.&#xd;
&#xd;
And I think it has become abundantly clear to most Americans, so much so that they tune them out, and I think it's one of the reasons that it's so important for the president to continue to speak directly to the American people, and I think it's one of the reasons they hate him so much because he doesn't need them. He goes around them and he can reach more people without the media than they can attacking him.&#xd;
&#xd;
And I think that's why he continues to be strong and he continues to do well, and the numbers reflect the good job that most people think he's doing.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: You know, Lara, you have a very esteemed history. I mean, you were war correspondents. You spent years of your life in war zones. You work on the news magazine, the ever so prestigious "60 Minutes", there's a compliment I say that to you. You don't particularly have a political agenda.&#xd;
&#xd;
I don't exactly want to put you on the spot, but I kind of do that for a living for people. How would you grade your colleagues in the media overall on their coverage of this, especially the president?&#xd;
&#xd;
LARA LOGAN, HOST OF "NO AGENDA WITH LARA LOGAN" ON FOX NATION: Well, I'm always mindful of course of the reporters who have done extraordinary work and I know you know how hard people work in on a breaking news story like this, Sean, as you do, right? But at the same time I do have to be honest because you asked me my opinion and I can't complain about him put on the spot that's what we do, and I don't -- I mean, for me, the media is not doing particularly well because, you know, we have that saying, don't let the facts get in the way of a good story, right? And that's said, ironically.&#xd;
&#xd;
But here, one of the most significant facts which is that something you point out all the time about the president's actions at the end of January on the travel ban. And those kinds of facts are left out of the narrative, and that's a problem because along with that are the opinions of millions of Americans who don't have a strictly negative view of this president or how this administration has handled this crisis.&#xd;
&#xd;
And really what should concern every journalist that there are the hallmarks of a smear campaign here, a typical ritual defamation campaign where the president is accused of racism and the whole conversation journalists are having is about racism without looking at the substance of the issue that you're dealing with, which is a virus that's come from China and all the related questions from that.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: Thank you both for being with us. Great insight from both of you.&#xd;
&#xd;
I think everyone in the media mob should answer to questions. I want to know in retrospect, did Donald Trump's travel ban ten days after the first known case in the United States, a coronavirus, was that the right thing to do? And as the president get credit -- would you give him credit in a month's time building 25,000 hospital beds, adding the personnel all over New York for Javits Center, for the comfort, all the ventilators that we were built, you give him any credit at all?&#xd;
&#xd;
The media needs to answer questions. I'd like to reverse roles on them.&#xd;
&#xd;
When we come back, Congresswoman Ocasio-Cortez celebrating the crash of the oil market. Yes, that means people will lose their jobs. Senator Lindsey Graham will weigh in.&#xd;
&#xd;
And later, officials are warning that China, they're upping their ante in the spy game against the United States and they you're not going to want to hear what we're going to tell you, but we're going to tell you anyway. That's what we do, straight ahead.&#xd;
&#xd;
(COMMERCIAL BREAK)&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: It's sad, but the far left finding even more ways to show its disdain for working Americans.&#xd;
&#xd;
Look at Congresswoman Ocasio-Cortez actually celebrating the impending job loss in the oil industry, writing in a now-deleted tweet: Well, you absolutely love to see it, in response to news of oil prices crashing.&#xd;
&#xd;
Education 101 for Congresswoman Ocasio-Cortez celebrating what will be economic hardship and a time of crisis in the oil industry, the lifeblood of the world's economy, although you don't quite seem to understand that. These are career jobs for people, and they're going to lose them -- just following the lead I guess of, well, designer ice cream lover Speaker Pelosi who continues to put petty politics above needed for American businesses.&#xd;
&#xd;
Remember, the speaker stonewalled the economic relief. That means for workers, for hospitals, for small businesses, for large businesses, caught downplaying the virus February 24th, has been defending China and the WHO despite obvious evidence of a massive cover-up that hurt this country.&#xd;
&#xd;
It's sick. It's ugly, twisted, not at all surprising and, of course, the mob and the media, they continue to spin for Pelosi. After a blistering Trump ad showing her hypocrisy and her $24,000 refrigerator and freezer, just listen to the ladies of the blue -- of "The View", that hard-hitting news show on ABC News. Take a look.&#xd;
&#xd;
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)&#xd;
&#xd;
JOY BEHAR, CO-HOST, THE VIEW: So this is just another distraction. You know, OK, it doesn't look good maybe. I mean, she's got an expensive refrigerator.&#xd;
&#xd;
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: That's just manufactured I think FOX News outrage and Republican outrage. You know, they're talking about "but her freezer, but her freezer", I'm really worried about the bodies that I saw being put into freezers in New York. That's what I'm worried about. I'm really worried about the fact that there are -- there's no testing being done.&#xd;
&#xd;
(END VIDEO CLIP)&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: Unfortunately, the disconnect between the left and reality is hitting every single corner of the Democratic Party.&#xd;
&#xd;
Listen to what the Pennsylvania governor had to say when asked this week about potential loopholes in the unemployment system that actually allow residents to make more money unemployed than when they are working. By the way, the people of Pennsylvania very loudly saying they want to go back to work. Take a look.&#xd;
&#xd;
(BEGIN VIDEO CLIP)&#xd;
&#xd;
UNIDENTIFIED FEMALE: A business owner asks if we have employees that are currently laid off and we call them back to work, and they tell us that they don't or won't come back because they're getting paid more with unemployment and the $600 bonus in a week that we're paying them. What can we do? Can their unemployment be revoked?&#xd;
&#xd;
GOV. TOM WOLF (D), PENNSYLVANIA: No, and as a former business owner, if you ever face that kind of situation, there's one really simple thing you can do as a business owner and that is raise the compensation of your employees.&#xd;
&#xd;
(END VIDEO CLIP)&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: Let's get Americans back to work safely.&#xd;
&#xd;
Also breaking tonight, Democratic governor in Michigan is in hot water after being caught hiring Democratic-linked firms to lead efforts to track the spread of coronavirus and collect health data.&#xd;
&#xd;
Here with reaction to all of this, Senator Lindsey Graham.&#xd;
&#xd;
Senator, you were the one that rightly pointed out you can't pay people --&#xd;
&#xd;
SEN. LINDSEY GRAHAM (R-SC): Yes.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: -- more money to stay at home.&#xd;
&#xd;
And, by the way, to the credit of the Pennsylvania people, they're fighting to go back to work, safely. We got to do it safely.&#xd;
&#xd;
GRAHAM: Right.&#xd;
&#xd;
Well, so let me just put this in context, I want to make sure that if you lose your job, if you're furloughed, you're laid off because of mitigation, you've done nothing wrong, we want to make sure that you receive a hundred percent of your pay, but what we don't want to do and unemployment is to pay you more than you actually received when you were working.&#xd;
&#xd;
Contrary to what the Pennsylvania governor says, it is not good for the economy to pay people more not to work than actually work, and that's what we're doing, and this has become a magnet to draw people out of the work force. We'll never have an economic recovery until we fix this. You should get a hundred percent of your wages up to $50,000, but you should never be paid more in unemployment than your employer pays you because that really skews the whole economy.&#xd;
&#xd;
And this guy in Pennsylvania doesn't get that. I bet you a lot of people in Pennsylvania do.&#xd;
&#xd;
And I want to ask him, do you agree with AOC that we should be excited about the destruction of the oil and gas industry? Ask the Pennsylvania governor who has a real oil and gas supply they're sitting on top on -- on top of, do you agree with her?&#xd;
&#xd;
Ask Joe Biden, hey, Joe, do you agree with AOC that we should be happy to destroy the oil and gas business in America?&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: Well, I think it's a great question.&#xd;
&#xd;
Now, Governor Whitmer of Michigan -- now, tomorrow, we're going to compare the response of Florida Governor DeSantis with Michigan governor, because she hasn't been doing so well, and for a lot of reasons, because she's made a lot of mistakes. Ron DeSantis did a lot of things right that he hasn't gotten credit for.&#xd;
&#xd;
But she just awarded a coronavirus response contract to a firm that actually had said on social media that they hope Donald Trump gets coronavirus.&#xd;
&#xd;
GRAHAM: Well, you can't make this stuff up, right? I mean, at the end of the day, the desire to destroy Donald Trump by the Democratic Party is greater than it is to destroy the virus.&#xd;
&#xd;
In January and February, they were impeaching the president. Nancy Pelosi sat on the articles of impeachment for almost a month. The trial didn't end of February the 6th and if it were to Chuck Schumer, we'd had witnesses all through February.&#xd;
&#xd;
So, my Democratic colleagues here have lost their way. All I can say is that the governor of Pennsylvania -- you're wrong, my friend, when you say it's good for the country to pay people more to be unemployed than to actually work. That's not good economics and most Americans are not looking for a pay raise in unemployment. They'd like to get their job back.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: Well, they would like to get their job back.&#xd;
&#xd;
There's never been a medical mobilization that has been this fast and in the end, everyone life matters. We believe it every life -- we want to save every America. We want to cure cancer and heart disease too. But never again.&#xd;
&#xd;
I want the questions asked of every Democrat running for Congress. I want that everyone in the media to answer it -- did the president make the right call as it relates to the travel ban ten days after the first known case in the U.S.? And did the president do a good job building 25,000 hospital beds, mobilizing and providing a personnel, mobilizing the private sector to build ventilators and all the shields and masks and respirators and gowns and gloves?&#xd;
&#xd;
GRAHAM: Right.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: Did he do anything good? Because according to them, they didn't, and he really had -- remember, even Dr. Fauci was saying the risk is low on February 29th.&#xd;
&#xd;
You know, China screwed everybody here.&#xd;
&#xd;
(CROSSTALK)&#xd;
&#xd;
GRAHAM: Can I read that quote for you?&#xd;
&#xd;
Yes, China is the bad guy, but I want you to ask that -- the left, do you agree that the CDC guidelines implemented by President Trump on March 13th saved millions of Americans from a terrible death? Do you agree that declaring a national emergency on March 13th mobilized this country to save lives? Do you agree that invoking the Defense Production Act really did help the medical supply chain we got to bring back from China?&#xd;
&#xd;
But on February the 29th, here's what Dr. Fauci said on "The Today Show", you need to put this in your list of quotes here.&#xd;
&#xd;
So this is the host Saturday: So, Dr. Fauci, Saturday morning in America, people were waking up right now with real concerns about this, they want to go to the malls, to movies, maybe the gym as well. Should we be changing our habits and if so how?&#xd;
&#xd;
Fauci: No. Right now, at this moment, there is no need to change anything you are doing on a day-to-day basis. Right now, the risk is still low, but this could change.&#xd;
&#xd;
That's on February the 29th, the smartest guy in America. I trust him. His best advice was on February 29th, it's OK to go to the gym, it's OK to go to the movie, it's OK to go to the mall.&#xd;
&#xd;
So, stop blaming Trump. That's what Fauci thought on February 29th. And by March the 13th, things did change and when things change --&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: And let me be clear --&#xd;
&#xd;
GRAHAM: -- the president acted. He --&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: And this guy's saved lives throughout his career. He's been a hero. We're not criticizing him.&#xd;
&#xd;
GRAHAM: Yes.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: We're making a point. China lied to everybody.&#xd;
&#xd;
GRAHAM: Yes.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: I got a run though.&#xd;
&#xd;
All right. Senator, thank you.&#xd;
&#xd;
GRAHAM: Including him, including him.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: Correct.&#xd;
&#xd;
Coming up, officials warning that China increasing its spying on U.S. soil. That report, straight ahead.&#xd;
&#xd;
(COMMERCIAL BREAK)&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: And now, even more major developments tonight surrounding China's propaganda efforts, because according to an explosive new report from foxnews.com, Beijing -- they're actually ramping up their spying efforts inside the U.S. to try and spread even more lies and deceit about their virus response failure.&#xd;
&#xd;
And it gets worse but there's drones being deployed to multiple law enforcement agencies all across the country to enforce social distancing -- well, they're tied to companies suspected of spying for China.&#xd;
&#xd;
And meanwhile, Beijing Biden is still trying to rewrite history, now trying to claim that the president went easy on China. It's the exact opposite that is true. Remember, Biden called the travel ban hysteria, xenophobic and fear-mongering, before taking months to change his mind two months and three days to be exact, even said last year that China wasn't a major threat.&#xd;
&#xd;
Here with reaction is author Gordon Chang and Iowa Senator Joni Ernst.&#xd;
&#xd;
Good to see you both.&#xd;
&#xd;
Senator, first, I know that like South Dakota, our meat processing plants are having these outbreaks. I know you're dealing with it in Iowa and Governor Kristi Noem in South Dakota. How's that going? And are you being able to mitigate it and get to the bottom of this?&#xd;
&#xd;
SEN. JONI ERNST (R-IA): Yes, working closely with a number of our federal government agencies, but also our Governor Kim Reynolds and the folks that we have in our state level agencies as well with those plan to owners, and we wish the best for those employees we want them working safely, but we know how critical our food supply chain is.&#xd;
&#xd;
So, we'll be working through this episode and again making sure that our food supply is safe, and those workers are healthy.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: I want to thank all of them. I want to thank packers, farmers, truckers, because I'm in the epicenter. Every store I go to is full and these guys that stock the shelves, they're doing dangerous work too and getting frontline medical people all the equipment, that -- they never stopped working either.&#xd;
&#xd;
Gordon, you understand China as well as anybody and have studied it. More and more, they seem like they didn't give a flying rip about -- they protected themselves, but they didn't care about anybody else in the world. How dangerous is this drone situation?&#xd;
&#xd;
GORDON CHANG, AUTHOR, "THE COMING COLLAPSE OF CHINA": Well, the drone situation we got to remember, Sean, is that these drones will send information images to the cloud. Once it goes into the cloud, it's in Beijing's hands.&#xd;
&#xd;
Also got to remember that in 2017, China passed its national intelligence law. That law requires every Chinese entity, every Chinese national to spy for Beijing if demanded.&#xd;
&#xd;
So although DJI, the drone company is nominally private, it is compelled to spy for Beijing and I'm sure that it does.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: Yes.&#xd;
&#xd;
Well -- and, Joni, look, they hold a lot of our debt, Senator.&#xd;
&#xd;
ERNST: Yes, they do.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: I'd like to know if maybe they should pay a lot of the cost because I'm getting concerned about the amount of money we're spending here. I want to take care of workers. I want to take care of small businesses. I want to take care of companies but I want to get America back to work safely.&#xd;
&#xd;
And I think China should foot some of the bill considering they knew how dangerous it was. They protected themselves but not the rest of the world.&#xd;
&#xd;
ERNST: Well, there are so many issues surrounding China and we can start, number one, by not sending any more taxpayer dollars to China, and that's where I do have a bill. It is a bipartisan bill by Merkley, Manchin, Braun, and me, which would stop American taxpayer dollars from going to those wet markets in China and the purchase by American taxpayer dollars of animals and parts coming out of those -- those markets. That's an easy start for us.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: Gordon, I don't understand the wet markets. I didn't even know what one was until a month ago.&#xd;
&#xd;
CHANG: Yes, well, the wet markets are where live animals were sold. And in many places, especially in China, you have very unhygienic conditions because you've got blood, you got urine, you got entrails on floor.&#xd;
&#xd;
(CROSSTALK)&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: What are you doing with these bats and exotic animals? What else is there?&#xd;
&#xd;
CHANG: Well, there's fish, there's all sorts of animals, and what they do is essentially sell them and sometimes slaughter them on-site, and that has created the unhygienic conditions.&#xd;
&#xd;
But one thing we know, Sean, is that China opened up these wet markets again at the end of March, which is a real indication that China knows that the coronavirus didn't come from the wet markets. It came from that P4 bio safety lab which everyone has been talking about, including the president of the United States. So, we know that this is from that lab.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: All right. Thank you both for being with us.&#xd;
&#xd;
When we come back to president is suspending --&#xd;
&#xd;
ERNST: Thanks.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: -- immigration for 60 days, saying Americans need to be first in line for new jobs. Probably Dan Bongino and I will gang up against Geraldo -- just a prediction -- straight ahead.&#xd;
&#xd;
(COMMERCIAL BREAK)&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: Now, the president is taking more bold decisive action to slow down the coronavirus pandemic and hopefully safe get the American people that want to go back to work back to work. He tweeted his intention last night to sign an executive order to temporarily shut down immigration, while America is recovering and getting our fellow Americans back to work for 60 days.&#xd;
&#xd;
Here with reaction, FOX News contributor Dan Bongino, FOX News correspondent at large, Geraldo Rivera.&#xd;
&#xd;
Quickly, Geraldo, OK, you want to come into our country, open arms, but we have to make sure you have no terror ties or drug cartel ties. Ninety percent of our heroin comes from the southern border. We have to have health checks going forward in my opinion. You have to be able to provide for yourself, I think that's important.&#xd;
&#xd;
And I think once we have those things, welcome to our family.&#xd;
&#xd;
GERALDO RIVERA, FOX NEWS CORRESPONDENT-AT-LARGE: You know, Sean, this presidential order, this executive order has to do with legal immigration. You know, you talked about the president taking bold decisive action to protect our food supply. The boldest most decisive action he can take he has taken. He has said that agricultural workers, the men and women who take the crops out of the ground and get it to the to the trucks to get it to that supermarket that you said was happily filled -- you know, those workers are exempt from this. So thank God agricultural workers are exempt.&#xd;
&#xd;
Basically, the people who are affected by this executive order are people who are coming in the front door. They're coming in legally. They're applying for green cards, and what the president has said is 60 days --&#xd;
&#xd;
(CROSSTALK)&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: Geraldo, we got 22 million Americans --&#xd;
&#xd;
RIVERA: -- he's suspending the program.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: We're not talking about sending anybody home that's here legally working, et cetera. That has already been approved.&#xd;
&#xd;
Dan Bongino, but going forward, the president was right and way ahead of the curve on two big issues, Dan, immigration and China.&#xd;
&#xd;
DAN BONGINO, FOX NEWS CONTRIBUTOR: Yes, yes, he was.&#xd;
&#xd;
You know, Sean, this was a perfectly logical decision. I can't understand why Geraldo would have any objection whatsoever. Number one, it's temporary. Secondly, we've seen some hot spots creeping up in the southern hemisphere. We don't even understand the R-zero, the contagiousness level of this disease yet.&#xd;
&#xd;
Why would you allow people in from other countries from potential hotspots? This is a temporary -- this is a temporary decision.&#xd;
&#xd;
And let me just say we're eating ourselves alive with political correctness that is preventing people in this media ecosystem from thinking clearly.&#xd;
&#xd;
You have a clearly dangerous virus that made its way into this country from foreign soil, the president's saying, until we can get our arms around this virus, maybe it's a good idea to restrict entrance from foreign soil, and there are people like no, that's a bad -- that doesn't make any sense.&#xd;
&#xd;
RIVERA: As a practical matter, this doesn't affect people coming in -- there's no flights coming in. There's not -- there are -- people aren't piling up. These are people already here on some other kind of visa waiting for their permanent status.&#xd;
&#xd;
These some of them have extraordinary abilities and arts or sciences --&#xd;
&#xd;
(CROSSTALK)&#xd;
&#xd;
RIVERA: They are coming in the front door. They're not coming in the back door.&#xd;
&#xd;
BONGINO: Geraldo, come on, man. Seriously, have you thought this thing through? It is a temporary restriction, temporary.&#xd;
&#xd;
RIVERA: Right.&#xd;
&#xd;
BONGINO: For 60 days.&#xd;
&#xd;
RIVERA: I can live with a 60-day suspension.&#xd;
&#xd;
BONGINO: And stop that, it doesn't affect the people here. It doesn't.&#xd;
&#xd;
(CROSSTALK)&#xd;
&#xd;
RIVERA: Yes, it does. Those are the people primarily -- those are the people who are panicked right now. People holding a tourist visa waiting to get in line for their green cards, these are people, you know --&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: All right, Geraldo --&#xd;
&#xd;
RIVERA: They're the --&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: Geraldo --&#xd;
&#xd;
RIVERA: We have to be practical --&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: Let's get the 22 million Americans back to work, first. Let's -- and as quickly and safely possible.&#xd;
&#xd;
BONGINO: You're not thinking (ph) about this logically, man. I'm sorry.&#xd;
&#xd;
RIVERA: We are a great country.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: We are, indeed. We'll leave it.&#xd;
&#xd;
A lot of questions tonight about Kim Jong-un's health. FOX News has learned the U.S. has an extensive contingency plan in case something happens. Trace Gallagher with that full, straight ahead.&#xd;
&#xd;
(COMMERCIAL BREAK)&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: North Korean leader and dictator Kim Jong-un's health is in question according to new reports.&#xd;
&#xd;
We have our chief breaking news correspondent Trace Gallagher live in our West Coast newsroom. He has the latest -- Trace.&#xd;
&#xd;
TRACE GALLAGHER, FOX NEWS CHIEF BREAKING NEWS CORRESPONDENT: Sean, national security adviser Robert O'Brien acknowledges North Korea is keeping this very close to the vest, but O'Brien says the intelligence community is very focused on Kim Jong-un's health and if his health is grave as some reports suggest, then intel is also looking to what external threats that might pose.&#xd;
&#xd;
Kim Jong-un reportedly underwent a recent heart procedure and has been absent at key events, including North Korea's most important holiday, the birthday celebration of his Kim's grandfather and founder of North Korea, Kim Il-sung.&#xd;
&#xd;
South Korea is knocking down reports that Kim Jong-un is in grave health, saying there's been no abnormal activity in North Korea -- Sean.&#xd;
&#xd;
HANNITY: All right. Trace, thanks for that update as always.&#xd;
&#xd;
And we'll always be fair and balanced. We're not the media mob.&#xd;
&#xd;
Let not your heart be troubled.&#xd;
&#xd;
Your shows have been great, Laura Ingraham, and I know you got a lot of breaking news tonight.</content>
</xwikidoc>